<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Houston Real Estate Video Blog with Mustafa Faiz</title>
    <description>Our mission at RE/MAX Signature is to be your best resource for Houston real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The RE/MAX Signature, your professional Houston Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 14:33:53 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 14:33:53 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Main Reasons Houston Real Estate Is So Hot</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/K8eI2eFQLZU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s a closer look at why real estate continues to remain strong.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two reasons why the real estate market is hot even though we are still in a pandemic and unemployment is still high:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Low interest rates&lt;br /&gt;2. Low inventory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s the perfect time to buy because of these low rates.%20http://localhost:4000/the-main-reasons-houston-real-estate-is-so-hot.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s the perfect time to buy because of these low rates.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look closer at the numbers, you’ll see that unemployment is only high in one or two industries. The hospitality and restaurant industries were completely decimated, but almost all other industries are doing just fine. Many people are working from home, and weekly earnings are still pretty high for most businesses. &lt;strong&gt;This gives many people the ability to purchase homes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean for you as a buyer or seller? If you’re planning on buying, this would be the perfect time because of the low interest rates. The competition will be fierce, but it will be worth the purchase in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For home sellers, you can &lt;strong&gt;expect to get your home sold fairly quickly if it’s priced and marketed right.&lt;/strong&gt; Keep in mind that the challenging part will be finding your next home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about the market or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 08:39:10 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-main-reasons-houston-real-estate-is-so-hot.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-main-reasons-houston-real-estate-is-so-hot.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Strategies That Will Get You the Home You Want</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hqQZVEaK1lE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s how you can find a home in a tough market like ours.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2020 as a whole was a hot seller’s market driven by low interest rates and low inventory. Those conditions have naturally spilled over into the new year, and they’re making it hard for buyers to find a good house, and if they do, there’s a good chance they’ll have to compete against other offers for it. Fortunately, if you are a buyer, there are three strategies my team and I have perfected that you can use to find an ideal off-market property you don’t have to compete for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Circle prospecting (within the community you’re looking to buy in).&lt;/strong&gt; For example, if a client is looking for a two-story home with a pool that’s somewhere between 2,500 and 3,000 square feet in the Alianna subdivision, we have the tools to identify such properties and call the homeowners to see if they’re interested in selling. Last year, using this strategy alone, we were able to find multiple properties for our clients. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=These strategies have been proven to work.%20http://localhost:4000/3-strategies-that-will-get-you-the-home-you-want.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“These strategies have been proven to work.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Online marketing.&lt;/strong&gt; In this case, we’d create a Facebook ad saying something to the effect of: “We have homebuyers who are looking for a two-story, 3,000-square-foot home in your neighborhood. If you’re seeing this ad and are interested in selling your property, please reach out to us!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Direct mail.&lt;/strong&gt; Nothing beats sending a good old-fashioned letter or postcard in the mail to potential home sellers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These strategies have been proven to work. Keep in mind, however, that they require a lot of time and effort from your real estate agent, so make sure you hire a good one. If you’d like to enlist my team’s help in finding your next home or have any questions about this topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 14:12:20 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-strategies-that-will-get-you-the-home-you-want.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-strategies-that-will-get-you-the-home-you-want.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Have You Filed for Your Homestead Exemption?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1VnTwmSjdks?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s a tip about how you can save money on your property taxes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a homestead exemption, you can save money every year on your property taxes. Say your home is worth $100,000; after getting a 20% discount (for example) with your homestead exemption, the county will assume the value of your property to be $80,000, and you’ll pay taxes on your home for that amount. There are several types of exemptions for which you could qualify. The most basic one is the homestead exemption, but there’s also the over-65 exemption, the disability property tax exemption, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you own the house with your spouse, you both need to apply individually.%20http://localhost:4000/have-you-filed-for-your-homestead-exemption.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you own the house with your spouse, you both need to apply individually.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The application period for your homestead exemption extends from January 1 to April 30.&lt;/strong&gt; Be sure to apply for yours during that window, especially if you bought a home in 2020. Filing for the exemption is a one-time process until you buy a new home, and it’s also pretty simple. In Harris County, for example, they have the HCAD app that you can download on your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you apply, you’ll need your driver’s license or your Texas state ID card that reflects the home address for which you’re applying for the exemption. Also, if you own the house with your spouse, you both need to apply individually; you will not be qualified for a full exemption if both of you do not apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about homestead exemptions, reach out to me. I’d be more than happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 09:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/have-you-filed-for-your-homestead-exemption.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/have-you-filed-for-your-homestead-exemption.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Which 3 Renovations Will Give You a Solid Return?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sKsr4kc6KzQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s a (purposefully) short list of renovations sellers should focus on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about renovating your home with the goal of selling it, then you should focus only on the following three areas of your home: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The kitchen.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you have granite countertops, stainless steel appliances if possible, and lighting that gives the space a bright, open feeling. That means replacing older fixtures with recessed lights, which are not that expensive. Creating the right ambiance here—one that’ll sway a buyer’s decision—requires less work than you might think. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Master bedroom and bathroom.&lt;/strong&gt; Again, proper lighting is critical, so make sure these areas appear bright and spacious. The granite countertops in the bathroom need to match what’s in the kitchen, so don’t try to force a totally separate theme. Also, replace older fixtures and mirrors to breathe new life into the space. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Brass is the past; brushed nickel is the way to go right now.%20http://localhost:4000/which-3-renovations-will-give-you-a-solid-return.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Brass is the past; brushed nickel is the way to go right now.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Fix odds and ends.&lt;/strong&gt; If there are older ceiling fans, doorknobs, or other such fixtures (especially anything brass) elsewhere in the house, go ahead and swap them out for new ones. Brass is the past; brushed nickel is the way to go right now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice this list doesn’t mention secondary bedrooms or bathrooms, or putting crown molding in every single room. Those are the things that you shouldn’t be spending your money on because you’ll see practically zero return on them—today’s buyers just don’t care. It’s okay to leave some room for buyers to undertake projects of their own, but do spend money strategically on the three areas I highlighted today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this or any other real estate topic, just reach out by phone or email. I’m here to help with your buying or selling needs, but I’m also happy to just be a resource for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 13:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/which-3-renovations-will-give-you-a-solid-return.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/which-3-renovations-will-give-you-a-solid-return.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wishing You a Happy Thanksgiving</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UnBZCRlTg1w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s what I’m grateful for this Thanksgiving.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2020 has been quite challenging for all of us, but now that Thanksgiving is here, it’s time for all of us to reflect on what we’re grateful for. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m grateful for the health and wellbeing of my family: my parents, siblings, wife, and children. I’m grateful we all have a roof over our heads and food on the table, and that we can still enjoy life’s simple pleasures. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s time for all of us to reflect on what we’re grateful for.%20http://localhost:4000/wishing-you-a-happy-thanksgiving.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s time for all of us to reflect on what we’re grateful for.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also thankful for all of my clients. &lt;strong&gt;You’ve put your faith in me and my team to help with your real estate needs, and that’s contributed to my life and livelihood.&lt;/strong&gt; This year has tested us and forced us to become a better version of ourselves. It’s made us adapt, become resilient, and respond to our circumstances, no matter how tough they may be. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you have many things to be grateful for this year—things that may seem trivial, but that you actually enjoy. I hope you have a wonderful Thanksgiving with your friends and family. If there’s anything I can help you with, real estate or otherwise, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 08:21:54 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/wishing-you-a-happy-thanksgiving.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/wishing-you-a-happy-thanksgiving.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Trick to Buying &amp; Selling Simultaneously?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EQobvdrc7b4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are three tips for how to buy and sell a house simultaneously.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we get clients who are looking to downsize, upsize, change location, or otherwise make a move that would require them to sell their current house even as they look for a new one. It is possible to pull these transactions off simultaneously, but there are three things you need to do to ensure that the process is as easy and stress-free as possible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Make sure you are 100% approved.&lt;/strong&gt; The next house you’re looking to buy could be in a different price range, so you need to meet with a loan officer to make sure you’re fully approved based on your current financial situation. You don’t want to find a buyer for your current home just to find out that you don’t even qualify for the new home. You also need to ensure that your buyer is fully approved. To make sure of that, we typically check to see if they have a pre-approval letter, but when the stakes are high, we add another layer of security by requesting the buyer be screened by your own loan officer. Now, the buyer isn’t obligated to use your loan officer; we’d simply ask them to be screened by them so we know if there will be issues down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Work with a flexible buyer.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t rush into a contract with just anyone willing to buy your home. Work with someone flexible about dates because remember; you’re still going to be working with another party on the purchase, and there might be some delays or other issues that may not be within your control. They need to be willing to move down the closing date or allow you to stay in your home after closing for a few weeks to give you extra time to move, depending on your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Don’t rush into a contract with just anyone willing to buy your home.%20http://localhost:4000/whats-the-trick-to-buying-selling-simultaneously.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Don’t rush into a contract with just anyone willing to buy your home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Work with just one title company.&lt;/strong&gt; You’ll want to limit the number of parties involved whenever you’re faced with this type of dual transaction. That will reduce the number of errors and omissions that might result from having multiple parties. You can request that the sellers of the home you’re trying to buy use the same title company that’s already processing your file, which will make things go more seamlessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about balancing transactions, reach out to us. My team and I would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 09:32:21 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-the-trick-to-buying-selling-simultaneously.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/whats-the-trick-to-buying-selling-simultaneously.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where Can You Find Nature in Houston?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IBy48xtLF6w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are my three favorite parks in Houston.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s video is a little bit different. Instead of covering buyer or seller tips, we’re going to look at real estate in a different way. I’m going to share my top three favorite Houston-area parks, which are all valuable pieces of real estate for what they provide to those who visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The one thing all of these three parks have in common is that they are great places to fish.&lt;/strong&gt; Most of the time, I don’t get lucky, but I always have fun. When I do catch something, it’s a bonus. All three of these parks are within the city of Houston, and you should check them out as soon as possible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Darren Goforth Park.&lt;/strong&gt; This is close to the Cyprus area. It has a huge lake, which has a great path around it for walking and running. There’s even a little dog beach, too. If you’re really into fishing, this is your top choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=All three of these parks are within the city of Houston.%20http://localhost:4000/where-can-you-find-nature-in-houston.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“All three of these parks are within the city of Houston.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Mary Jo Peckham Park.&lt;/strong&gt; This isn’t as big as the others, but it has so many trees and greenery along with lots of shade and even mini islands. Not a lot of people know about it, but it’s truly a hidden gem in the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Kickerillo-Mischer Preserve.&lt;/strong&gt; This park has been my favorite to visit. It’s as close as you can get to nature within the city of Houston. It’s in the northwest area of town right off of 249. I love going there to be present in nature, have a picnic, do some fishing, or just get some exercise. This spot is famous for bird watching as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know you’re going to love all three of these parks. If you have any others that I should add to my list or want to tell me about your experiences, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I’d love to talk with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 14:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/where-can-you-find-nature-in-houston.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/where-can-you-find-nature-in-houston.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Three Ways To Get Your Offer Accepted As A Home Buyer</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uB6u7JuV34o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Buyers: Here are three things you must consider when writing your offer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re an active buyer in this pandemic-impacted 2020 market, you’ve experienced firsthand the craziness that’s been making headlines. Homes, especially those in the $300,000 range, are flying off the market with multiple offers. We’re seeing an influx of buyers to the market and a shortage of houses, which is ramping up competition and pushing prices a bit higher. So, how can you give the offer the highest chance of success? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Do not ask the seller to pay your closing costs.&lt;/strong&gt; That strategy works in markets where there’s plenty of homes to choose from, but in a strong seller’s market like ours, keep it fair—let the seller pay their closing costs, and agree to pay your own. You can always renegotiate later on, but you should at least avoid asking for this up front. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Get rid of that financing contingency.&lt;/strong&gt; About 97% of buyers are asking the seller to give them about 21 days so they can try to get approval for a loan. For the seller, that’s 21 days of risk; the buyer may or may not get approved. Just imagine how impactful it’d be if you went to the seller and said, “Here’s my offer. By the way, I’m fully approved, so I’m not asking you to give me 21 days.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever wondered why a seller selected another offer over yours, it’s because that winning buyer was one of the 3% of buyers who sought full approval beforehand. If you can get approved and eliminate this contingency, it’ll make your offer as good as a cash offer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Odds are good that your competition isn’t aware of these strategies.%20http://localhost:4000/three-ways-to-get-your-offer-accepted-as-a-home-buyer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Odds are good that your competition isn’t aware of these strategies.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Shorten the length of your inspection period.&lt;/strong&gt; A lot of other buyers will be asking for 10 to 15 days for the inspection, during which time the buyer can back out of the deal. Essentially, they’re telling the seller that you need them to wait 15 days so you can inspect the property, and if the results displease you, they’ll hit the road. What if you offered seven days instead of 15? It communicates that you’re a serious buyer who’s not interested in wasting anyone’s time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you implement these three techniques, you’ll position yourself strongly in the top 3% of buyers out there. Even if you’re competing for the home of your dreams against 10 other offers, the odds are good that your competition isn’t aware of these strategies. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about anything real estate-related or there’s a topic you’d like me to cover in an upcoming video, please reach out via phone or email. I’d be happy to discuss any of these principles in greater detail and hear about your particular situation. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 15:05:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/three-ways-to-get-your-offer-accepted-as-a-home-buyer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/three-ways-to-get-your-offer-accepted-as-a-home-buyer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Real Estate Commissions Explained</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gOsYZyN-4Uo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here’s a quick summary of how real estate commissions work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real estate is a service industry, and we agents rely exclusively on commissions to get paid. Of course, a commission only gets doled out if a transaction occurs. You could be working with an agent for months at a time trying to buy or sell a home, but if a transaction doesn’t eventually transpire, no one gets paid; all of that time and effort goes to waste. To give you some insight on how this industry really works, today I’ll explain how commissions are structured for both buyer and seller agents. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch it in its entirety or use these timestamps to browse specific points at your leisure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:44—What listing agents charge and how their fee is broken down&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2:22—How brokerages have their own payment structure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3:24—The fiduciary responsibilities of buyer agents and what they charge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:07—The importance of discussing commission fees with your agent &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5:51—Wrapping things up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this or any other real estate topic or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’m happy to help. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 08:39:27 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/real-estate-commissions-explained.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/real-estate-commissions-explained.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: Which Down Payment Assistance Programs Can Help You?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TNSR3lrT5uo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of buying a home, there are several down payment assistance programs that encourage homeownership here in Texas. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The money they provide varies from person to person, but it generally ranges from $5,000 to $17,000. &lt;strong&gt;One of the main benefits of these programs is that the minimum credit score to qualify for them remains at just 620.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’ve been following the mortgage industry lately, you know that many banks and mortgage companies have increased their minimum credit score. Some aren’t even considering applications from anyone with a score of less than 700. At the same time, the interest rate will be the same as a conventional or FHA loan. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, sellers can contribute to the closing costs so that you end up paying very little out of pocket. In these cases, the earnest money, inspection fees, and appraisal fees are the only costs you’d pay out of pocket. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are several down payment assistance programs that encourage homeownership here in Texas.%20http://localhost:4000/q-which-down-payment-assistance-programs-can-help-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are several down payment assistance programs that encourage homeownership here in Texas.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a better idea of what kind of assistance you’d receive, here are some recent examples of purchase prices of homes that closed in 30 days or less:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$285,000: With an interest rate of 3.875%, the buyer received $11,193&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$205,000: With an interest rate of 3.25%, the buyer received $6,038&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$158,000: With an interest rate of 3.75%, the buyer received $6,206&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$250,000: With an interest rate of 3.25%, the buyer received $9,818&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the more popular down payment assistance programs, their benefits, and their requirements: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. SETH (Southeast Texas Housing Finance Corp).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offers a grant of up to 5% of the loan amount&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minimum credit score: 640&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maximum purchase price: $484,350&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maximum income: $90,620 (does not have to be both borrowers’ income)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You don’t have to be a first-time buyer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conventional, FHA, VA, and USDA loans allowed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Down payment assistance for up to 5% of the loan amount&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rates as low as 2.75%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. TDHCA (Texas Department of Housing and Community Affairs)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;TDHCA Program 79 offers a second lien of 5% of the loan amount (There are no payments and no interest on the second lien—it is paid off when the house is sold or refinanced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minimum credit score: 620&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maximum purchase price: $294,600 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maximum income: $90,620&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You don’t have to be a first-time buyer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mortgage credit certificate can be combined&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Down payment assistance for up to 5% of the loan amount&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rates as low as 2.75%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. TSAHC (Texas State Affordable Housing Corp)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offers the Texas Heroes Program for teachers, police officers, firemen, veterans, and others—as well as the Home Sweet Home Program for everyone else&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offers a non-repayable grant or bond for up to 5% of the loan amount&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minimum credit score: 620&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maximum purchase price: $294,600&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maximum income: $90,620 (does not have to use both borrowers’ income)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You don’t have to be a first-time buyer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Down payment assistance for up to 5% of the loan amount&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rates as low as 3%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. MCC (Mortgage Credit Certificate) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll receive a 20% to 25% tax credit on the interest you pay each year you have the mortgage with a maximum of $2,000 per year. This gives you the ability to lower the taxes taken out of your paycheck or possibly receive cash back when you file your taxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know more about these and other programs, talk to a loan officer who’s familiar with them—not every loan officer knows how they work. I know plenty of excellent loan officers I’d be happy to refer you to, so just give me a call if you’d like to know more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have questions about this or any real estate topic, feel free to reach out to me as well. I’m here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 14:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-which-down-payment-assistance-programs-can-help-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-which-down-payment-assistance-programs-can-help-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
