<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Houston Real Estate Podcast with Mustafa Faiz</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from RE/MAX Signature - your professional Houston Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Mustafa Faiz</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2021-02-15 14:33:53 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Mustafa Faiz</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>mfaiz@remax.net</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Houston Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from RE/MAX Signature - your professional Houston Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Main Reasons Houston Real Estate Is So Hot</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-main-reasons-houston-real-estate-is-so-hot.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2021-02-09 08:39:10 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/The+Main+Reasons+Houston+Real+Estate+Is+So+Hot.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here’s a closer look at why real estate continues to remain strong.

There are two reasons why the real estate market is hot even though we are still in a pandemic and unemployment is still high:

1. Low interest rates2. Low inventory

“It’s the perfect time to buy because of these low rates.”

If you look closer at the numbers, you’ll see that unemployment is only high in one or two industries. The hospitality and restaurant industries were completely decimated, but almost all other industries are doing just fine. Many people are working from home, and weekly earnings are still pretty high for most businesses. This gives many people the ability to purchase homes.

What does this mean for you as a buyer or seller? If you’re planning on buying, this would be the perfect time because of the low interest rates. The competition will be fierce, but it will be worth the purchase in the long run.

For home sellers, you can expect to get your home sold fairly quickly if it’s priced and marketed right. Keep in mind that the challenging part will be finding your next home.

If you have any questions for me about the market or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/The+Main+Reasons+Houston+Real+Estate+Is+So+Hot.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/The+Main+Reasons+Houston+Real+Estate+Is+So+Hot.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s a closer look at why real estate continues to remain strong.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s a closer look at why real estate continues to remain strong.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Strategies That Will Get You the Home You Want</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-strategies-that-will-get-you-the-home-you-want.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2021-01-21 14:12:20 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/3+Strategies+That+Will+Get+You+the+Home+You+Want.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here’s how you can find a home in a tough market like ours.

2020 as a whole was a hot seller’s market driven by low interest rates and low inventory. Those conditions have naturally spilled over into the new year, and they’re making it hard for buyers to find a good house, and if they do, there’s a good chance they’ll have to compete against other offers for it. Fortunately, if you are a buyer, there are three strategies my team and I have perfected that you can use to find an ideal off-market property you don’t have to compete for:

1. Circle prospecting (within the community you’re looking to buy in). For example, if a client is looking for a two-story home with a pool that’s somewhere between 2,500 and 3,000 square feet in the Alianna subdivision, we have the tools to identify such properties and call the homeowners to see if they’re interested in selling. Last year, using this strategy alone, we were able to find multiple properties for our clients. 

“These strategies have been proven to work.”

2. Online marketing. In this case, we’d create a Facebook ad saying something to the effect of: “We have homebuyers who are looking for a two-story, 3,000-square-foot home in your neighborhood. If you’re seeing this ad and are interested in selling your property, please reach out to us!”

3. Direct mail. Nothing beats sending a good old-fashioned letter or postcard in the mail to potential home sellers. 

These strategies have been proven to work. Keep in mind, however, that they require a lot of time and effort from your real estate agent, so make sure you hire a good one. If you’d like to enlist my team’s help in finding your next home or have any questions about this topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/3+Strategies+That+Will+Get+You+the+Home+You+Want.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/3+Strategies+That+Will+Get+You+the+Home+You+Want.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s how you can find a home in a tough market like ours.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s how you can find a home in a tough market like ours.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Have You Filed for Your Homestead Exemption?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/have-you-filed-for-your-homestead-exemption.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2021-01-07 09:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Have+You+Filed+for+Your+Homestead+Exemption_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here’s a tip about how you can save money on your property taxes.

With a homestead exemption, you can save money every year on your property taxes. Say your home is worth $100,000; after getting a 20% discount (for example) with your homestead exemption, the county will assume the value of your property to be $80,000, and you’ll pay taxes on your home for that amount. There are several types of exemptions for which you could qualify. The most basic one is the homestead exemption, but there’s also the over-65 exemption, the disability property tax exemption, and more.

“If you own the house with your spouse, you both need to apply individually.”

The application period for your homestead exemption extends from January 1 to April 30. Be sure to apply for yours during that window, especially if you bought a home in 2020. Filing for the exemption is a one-time process until you buy a new home, and it’s also pretty simple. In Harris County, for example, they have the HCAD app that you can download on your phone.

When you apply, you’ll need your driver’s license or your Texas state ID card that reflects the home address for which you’re applying for the exemption. Also, if you own the house with your spouse, you both need to apply individually; you will not be qualified for a full exemption if both of you do not apply.

If you have any questions about homestead exemptions, reach out to me. I’d be more than happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Have+You+Filed+for+Your+Homestead+Exemption_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Have+You+Filed+for+Your+Homestead+Exemption_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s a tip about how you can save money on your property taxes.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s a tip about how you can save money on your property taxes.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Which 3 Renovations Will Give You a Solid Return?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/which-3-renovations-will-give-you-a-solid-return.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2020-12-03 13:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Which+3+Renovations+Will+Give+You+a+Solid+Return_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here’s a (purposefully) short list of renovations sellers should focus on.

If you’re thinking about renovating your home with the goal of selling it, then you should focus only on the following three areas of your home: 

1. The kitchen. Make sure you have granite countertops, stainless steel appliances if possible, and lighting that gives the space a bright, open feeling. That means replacing older fixtures with recessed lights, which are not that expensive. Creating the right ambiance here—one that’ll sway a buyer’s decision—requires less work than you might think. 

2. Master bedroom and bathroom. Again, proper lighting is critical, so make sure these areas appear bright and spacious. The granite countertops in the bathroom need to match what’s in the kitchen, so don’t try to force a totally separate theme. Also, replace older fixtures and mirrors to breathe new life into the space. 

“Brass is the past; brushed nickel is the way to go right now.”

3. Fix odds and ends. If there are older ceiling fans, doorknobs, or other such fixtures (especially anything brass) elsewhere in the house, go ahead and swap them out for new ones. Brass is the past; brushed nickel is the way to go right now. 

Notice this list doesn’t mention secondary bedrooms or bathrooms, or putting crown molding in every single room. Those are the things that you shouldn’t be spending your money on because you’ll see practically zero return on them—today’s buyers just don’t care. It’s okay to leave some room for buyers to undertake projects of their own, but do spend money strategically on the three areas I highlighted today. 

As always, if you have questions about this or any other real estate topic, just reach out by phone or email. I’m here to help with your buying or selling needs, but I’m also happy to just be a resource for you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Which+3+Renovations+Will+Give+You+a+Solid+Return_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Which+3+Renovations+Will+Give+You+a+Solid+Return_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s a (purposefully) short list of renovations sellers should focus on.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s a (purposefully) short list of renovations sellers should focus on.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Wishing You a Happy Thanksgiving</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/wishing-you-a-happy-thanksgiving.html</link>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2020-11-18 08:21:54 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Wishing+you+a+happy+Thanksgiving.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here’s what I’m grateful for this Thanksgiving.

2020 has been quite challenging for all of us, but now that Thanksgiving is here, it’s time for all of us to reflect on what we’re grateful for. 

I’m grateful for the health and wellbeing of my family: my parents, siblings, wife, and children. I’m grateful we all have a roof over our heads and food on the table, and that we can still enjoy life’s simple pleasures. 

“It’s time for all of us to reflect on what we’re grateful for.”

I’m also thankful for all of my clients. You’ve put your faith in me and my team to help with your real estate needs, and that’s contributed to my life and livelihood. This year has tested us and forced us to become a better version of ourselves. It’s made us adapt, become resilient, and respond to our circumstances, no matter how tough they may be. 

I hope you have many things to be grateful for this year—things that may seem trivial, but that you actually enjoy. I hope you have a wonderful Thanksgiving with your friends and family. If there’s anything I can help you with, real estate or otherwise, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Wishing+you+a+happy+Thanksgiving.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Wishing+you+a+happy+Thanksgiving.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s what I’m grateful for this Thanksgiving.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s what I’m grateful for this Thanksgiving.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Trick to Buying & Selling Simultaneously?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-the-trick-to-buying-selling-simultaneously.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2020-11-05 09:32:21 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Whats+the+Trick+to+Buying+%26+Selling+Simultaneously_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here are three tips for how to buy and sell a house simultaneously.

Sometimes we get clients who are looking to downsize, upsize, change location, or otherwise make a move that would require them to sell their current house even as they look for a new one. It is possible to pull these transactions off simultaneously, but there are three things you need to do to ensure that the process is as easy and stress-free as possible:

1. Make sure you are 100% approved. The next house you’re looking to buy could be in a different price range, so you need to meet with a loan officer to make sure you’re fully approved based on your current financial situation. You don’t want to find a buyer for your current home just to find out that you don’t even qualify for the new home. You also need to ensure that your buyer is fully approved. To make sure of that, we typically check to see if they have a pre-approval letter, but when the stakes are high, we add another layer of security by requesting the buyer be screened by your own loan officer. Now, the buyer isn’t obligated to use your loan officer; we’d simply ask them to be screened by them so we know if there will be issues down the road.

2. Work with a flexible buyer. Don’t rush into a contract with just anyone willing to buy your home. Work with someone flexible about dates because remember; you’re still going to be working with another party on the purchase, and there might be some delays or other issues that may not be within your control. They need to be willing to move down the closing date or allow you to stay in your home after closing for a few weeks to give you extra time to move, depending on your needs.

“Don’t rush into a contract with just anyone willing to buy your home.”

3. Work with just one title company. You’ll want to limit the number of parties involved whenever you’re faced with this type of dual transaction. That will reduce the number of errors and omissions that might result from having multiple parties. You can request that the sellers of the home you’re trying to buy use the same title company that’s already processing your file, which will make things go more seamlessly.

If you have any more questions about balancing transactions, reach out to us. My team and I would love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Whats+the+Trick+to+Buying+%26+Selling+Simultaneously_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Whats+the+Trick+to+Buying+%26+Selling+Simultaneously_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are three tips for how to buy and sell a house simultaneously.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are three tips for how to buy and sell a house simultaneously.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Where Can You Find Nature in Houston?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/where-can-you-find-nature-in-houston.html</link>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2020-09-09 14:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Where+Can+You+Find+Nature+in+Houston_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here are my three favorite parks in Houston.

Today’s video is a little bit different. Instead of covering buyer or seller tips, we’re going to look at real estate in a different way. I’m going to share my top three favorite Houston-area parks, which are all valuable pieces of real estate for what they provide to those who visit.

The one thing all of these three parks have in common is that they are great places to fish. Most of the time, I don’t get lucky, but I always have fun. When I do catch something, it’s a bonus. All three of these parks are within the city of Houston, and you should check them out as soon as possible:

3. Darren Goforth Park. This is close to the Cyprus area. It has a huge lake, which has a great path around it for walking and running. There’s even a little dog beach, too. If you’re really into fishing, this is your top choice.

“All three of these parks are within the city of Houston.”

2. Mary Jo Peckham Park. This isn’t as big as the others, but it has so many trees and greenery along with lots of shade and even mini islands. Not a lot of people know about it, but it’s truly a hidden gem in the city.

1. Kickerillo-Mischer Preserve. This park has been my favorite to visit. It’s as close as you can get to nature within the city of Houston. It’s in the northwest area of town right off of 249. I love going there to be present in nature, have a picnic, do some fishing, or just get some exercise. This spot is famous for bird watching as well.

I know you’re going to love all three of these parks. If you have any others that I should add to my list or want to tell me about your experiences, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I’d love to talk with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Where+Can+You+Find+Nature+in+Houston_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Where+Can+You+Find+Nature+in+Houston_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are my three favorite parks in Houston.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are my three favorite parks in Houston.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Three Ways To Get Your Offer Accepted As A Home Buyer</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/three-ways-to-get-your-offer-accepted-as-a-home-buyer.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2020-08-24 15:05:50 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Three+Techniques+97%25+of+Buyers+Fail.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Buyers: Here are three things you must consider when writing your offer.

If you’re an active buyer in this pandemic-impacted 2020 market, you’ve experienced firsthand the craziness that’s been making headlines. Homes, especially those in the $300,000 range, are flying off the market with multiple offers. We’re seeing an influx of buyers to the market and a shortage of houses, which is ramping up competition and pushing prices a bit higher. So, how can you give the offer the highest chance of success? 

1. Do not ask the seller to pay your closing costs. That strategy works in markets where there’s plenty of homes to choose from, but in a strong seller’s market like ours, keep it fair—let the seller pay their closing costs, and agree to pay your own. You can always renegotiate later on, but you should at least avoid asking for this up front. 

2. Get rid of that financing contingency. About 97% of buyers are asking the seller to give them about 21 days so they can try to get approval for a loan. For the seller, that’s 21 days of risk; the buyer may or may not get approved. Just imagine how impactful it’d be if you went to the seller and said, “Here’s my offer. By the way, I’m fully approved, so I’m not asking you to give me 21 days.” 

If you’ve ever wondered why a seller selected another offer over yours, it’s because that winning buyer was one of the 3% of buyers who sought full approval beforehand. If you can get approved and eliminate this contingency, it’ll make your offer as good as a cash offer. 

“Odds are good that your competition isn’t aware of these strategies.”

3. Shorten the length of your inspection period. A lot of other buyers will be asking for 10 to 15 days for the inspection, during which time the buyer can back out of the deal. Essentially, they’re telling the seller that you need them to wait 15 days so you can inspect the property, and if the results displease you, they’ll hit the road. What if you offered seven days instead of 15? It communicates that you’re a serious buyer who’s not interested in wasting anyone’s time. 

If you implement these three techniques, you’ll position yourself strongly in the top 3% of buyers out there. Even if you’re competing for the home of your dreams against 10 other offers, the odds are good that your competition isn’t aware of these strategies. 

As always, if you have questions about anything real estate-related or there’s a topic you’d like me to cover in an upcoming video, please reach out via phone or email. I’d be happy to discuss any of these principles in greater detail and hear about your particular situation. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Three+Techniques+97%25+of+Buyers+Fail.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Three+Techniques+97%25+of+Buyers+Fail.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Buyers: Here are three things you must consider when writing your offer.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Buyers: Here are three things you must consider when writing your offer.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Real Estate Commissions Explained</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/real-estate-commissions-explained.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2020-08-05 08:39:27 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Real+Estate+Commissions+Explained.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here’s a quick summary of how real estate commissions work.

Real estate is a service industry, and we agents rely exclusively on commissions to get paid. Of course, a commission only gets doled out if a transaction occurs. You could be working with an agent for months at a time trying to buy or sell a home, but if a transaction doesn’t eventually transpire, no one gets paid; all of that time and effort goes to waste. To give you some insight on how this industry really works, today I’ll explain how commissions are structured for both buyer and seller agents. 

Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch it in its entirety or use these timestamps to browse specific points at your leisure:

1:44—What listing agents charge and how their fee is broken down

2:22—How brokerages have their own payment structure

3:24—The fiduciary responsibilities of buyer agents and what they charge

5:07—The importance of discussing commission fees with your agent 

5:51—Wrapping things up

As always, if you have questions about this or any other real estate topic or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’m happy to help. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Real+Estate+Commissions+Explained.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Real+Estate+Commissions+Explained.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s a quick summary of how real estate commissions work.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s a quick summary of how real estate commissions work.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: Which Down Payment Assistance Programs Can Help You?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-which-down-payment-assistance-programs-can-help-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2020-07-22 14:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Q-+Which+Down+Payment+Assistance+Programs+Can+You+Take+Advantage+Of_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking of buying a home, there are several down payment assistance programs that encourage homeownership here in Texas. 

The money they provide varies from person to person, but it generally ranges from $5,000 to $17,000. One of the main benefits of these programs is that the minimum credit score to qualify for them remains at just 620. If you’ve been following the mortgage industry lately, you know that many banks and mortgage companies have increased their minimum credit score. Some aren’t even considering applications from anyone with a score of less than 700. At the same time, the interest rate will be the same as a conventional or FHA loan. 

Additionally, sellers can contribute to the closing costs so that you end up paying very little out of pocket. In these cases, the earnest money, inspection fees, and appraisal fees are the only costs you’d pay out of pocket. 

“There are several down payment assistance programs that encourage homeownership here in Texas.”

To get a better idea of what kind of assistance you’d receive, here are some recent examples of purchase prices of homes that closed in 30 days or less:


  $285,000: With an interest rate of 3.875%, the buyer received $11,193
  $205,000: With an interest rate of 3.25%, the buyer received $6,038
  $158,000: With an interest rate of 3.75%, the buyer received $6,206
  $250,000: With an interest rate of 3.25%, the buyer received $9,818


Here are some of the more popular down payment assistance programs, their benefits, and their requirements: 

1. SETH (Southeast Texas Housing Finance Corp).


  Offers a grant of up to 5% of the loan amount
  Minimum credit score: 640
  Maximum purchase price: $484,350
  Maximum income: $90,620 (does not have to be both borrowers’ income)
  You don’t have to be a first-time buyer
  Conventional, FHA, VA, and USDA loans allowed
  Down payment assistance for up to 5% of the loan amount
  Rates as low as 2.75%


2. TDHCA (Texas Department of Housing and Community Affairs)


  TDHCA Program 79 offers a second lien of 5% of the loan amount (There are no payments and no interest on the second lien—it is paid off when the house is sold or refinanced)
  Minimum credit score: 620
  Maximum purchase price: $294,600 
  Maximum income: $90,620
  You don’t have to be a first-time buyer
  Mortgage credit certificate can be combined
  Down payment assistance for up to 5% of the loan amount
  Rates as low as 2.75%


3. TSAHC (Texas State Affordable Housing Corp)


  Offers the Texas Heroes Program for teachers, police officers, firemen, veterans, and others—as well as the Home Sweet Home Program for everyone else
  Offers a non-repayable grant or bond for up to 5% of the loan amount
  Minimum credit score: 620
  Maximum purchase price: $294,600
  Maximum income: $90,620 (does not have to use both borrowers’ income)
  You don’t have to be a first-time buyer
  Down payment assistance for up to 5% of the loan amount
  Rates as low as 3%


4. MCC (Mortgage Credit Certificate) 


  You’ll receive a 20% to 25% tax credit on the interest you pay each year you have the mortgage with a maximum of $2,000 per year. This gives you the ability to lower the taxes taken out of your paycheck or possibly receive cash back when you file your taxes.


If you’d like to know more about these and other programs, talk to a loan officer who’s familiar with them—not every loan officer knows how they work. I know plenty of excellent loan officers I’d be happy to refer you to, so just give me a call if you’d like to know more. 

As always, if you have questions about this or any real estate topic, feel free to reach out to me as well. I’m here to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Q-+Which+Down+Payment+Assistance+Programs+Can+You+Take+Advantage+Of_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Q-+Which+Down+Payment+Assistance+Programs+Can+You+Take+Advantage+Of_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are several down payment assistance programs you can take advantage of.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are several down payment assistance programs you can take advantage of.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to See Coming Soon Listings Before Any Home Buyers</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-see-coming-soon-listings-before-your-competition.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2020-06-24 11:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/How+to+See+Coming+Soon+Listings+Before+Your+Competition.mp4</guid>
        <description>

An amazing new feature allows you to see listings that aren’t even on the market yet.

The Houston Association of Realtors recently launched an amazing new feature that allows real estate agents to see what properties are going to be coming soon on the market. These listings are not available to the public—you won’t even find them on websites like Zillow or Realtor.com! However, since it is available to real estate agents, I would be more than happy to share this new feature with you. This technology gives buyers the benefit of a heads up on which properties are going to be listed within the next two weeks. 

Some of the properties have pictures, allowing you to scroll through the photos to get a glimpse that other competing buyers won’t get. Many of these listings may not have photos, but all of them have the essential information like pricing, size, bedrooms, bathrooms, etc. With this feature, we can get a head start on communicating with the seller’s agents and be the first ones to see a home and make an offer on it.

If you have any questions or would like to view properties coming soon to the market, don’t hesitate to reach out. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/How+to+See+Coming+Soon+Listings+Before+Your+Competition.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/How+to+See+Coming+Soon+Listings+Before+Your+Competition.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>An amazing new feature allows you to see listings that aren’t even on the market yet.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>An amazing new feature allows you to see listings that aren’t even on the market yet.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: How Can You Buy/Sell a Home With Owner Financing?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-how-can-you-buysell-a-home-with-owner-financing.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2020-06-10 09:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Q-+How+Can+You+Buy-Sell+a+Home+With+Owner+Financing_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today’s topic is owner financing. We’ll discuss the benefits and disadvantages of this method from both a buyer’s and seller’s perspective.

If you’re a homeowner who is thinking about selling the property on owner financing terms instead of renting it out or selling it to a conventional buyer, the advantages are clear. You’ll be able to generate a pure income, for example. When you sell through owner financing, you won’t incur any additional expenses. 

Another benefit is maintenance. It’s something you will have to worry about if you rent a home out, but won’t be an issue if you just sell outright. Finally, it’s an ideal investment vehicle.

As far as the disadvantages are concerned, selling the property will mean you have no right to future appreciation. It also comes with additional tax implications and fewer write off opportunities.

“Not all homes are available to purchase through owner financing.”

Now let’s talk about the pros and cons for buyers with owner financing. If you can’t get qualified for a regular mortgage, owner financing is the next best vehicle for purchasing a home. Your monthly mortgage payment will likely be equal to or even less than what you’re paying in rent right now. Owner financing allows more homebuyers to qualify for a purchase now and refinance down the road to get more favorable terms. 

The other pro is the tax benefits I discussed earlier. Owning a home allows you to write off certain expenses to ease your tax burden.

The biggest con to buying a home with owner financing is the interest rate. Regular interest rates are around 3% or 4%, but owner financing rates are from 8% to 10%. These aren’t intended to be 30-year mortgages. The objective of buying with owner financing is working on your credit after you get the mortgage, then refinancing to a lower rate down the line. 

Keep in mind that not all homes are available for purchase through owner financing. You should ask your agent about this if you’re considering it. I can send you a list of these properties, too.

If you have any questions for me about buying or selling a home with owner financing, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Q-+How+Can+You+Buy-Sell+a+Home+With+Owner+Financing_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Q-+How+Can+You+Buy-Sell+a+Home+With+Owner+Financing_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Owner financing is another option if a conventional mortgage won’t work.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Owner financing is another option if a conventional mortgage won’t work.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Can We Expect for Real Estate in Summer 2020?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-can-we-expect-for-real-estate-in-summer-2020.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2020-05-29 11:23:24 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Q-+What+Can+We+Expect+for+Real+Estate+in+Summer+2020_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Things are heating up, and I don't just mean the weather...

Week after week, for the past five weeks, the Mortgage Bankers Association has reported record-setting numbers of mortgage applications. This means more and more people have been applying for mortgage loans as they get ready to transact within the next three to six months. 

The interest rates are still low, averaging about 3.25%, which is great news for buyers in the Houston area. These signs of a strong and healthy market are also great for Houston area homeowners, especially those who feared that prices would drop and the market would crash; none of that is happening, and we have no reason to believe it will. 

We were in the spring market when lockdown started, so a lot of buyers who had been gearing up for an early 2020 purchase could no longer follow through on their goals. Now, those buyers on pause are hitting the ‘play’ button, and adding to the pool of buyers who’ve recently been enticed to act thanks to incredibly low rates. With all of this pent-up demand, we can expect a massive influx of buyers in the summer market. 

“As we begin this summer season, I’m personally noticing more and more activity.”

Governor Gregg Abbot has announced Phase II of reopening our state economy, which affects the status of open houses. Under lockdown, we were not allowed to conduct open houses in our real estate market, but as recently as this week these restrictions have been lifted. This is great for sellers since it’ll mean greater exposure for your home. For buyers frustrated with the idea of virtual tours and photo browsing, it means you’ll finally have more opportunities to check out a home in person. 

Now, keep in mind we are still following CDC guidelines, which means we’ll be doing everything we can to minimize contact and maximize sanitation. 

As we begin this summer season, I’m personally noticing more and more activity. My buyers and I are safely touring more homes now than we were about a month ago. On some of our listings that went live just a few weeks ago, we’re seeing multiple showings—three or four every day. We’re seeing houses go under contract within days of being listed, and multiple-offer scenarios are still a common affair. 

Overall, this is very encouraging news for all of us. I hope to have more news to report to you soon. In the meantime, reach out to me with any questions or concerns you may have. I’d love to be of assistance. Stay safe, and have a wonderful day!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Q-+What+Can+We+Expect+for+Real+Estate+in+Summer+2020_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Q-+What+Can+We+Expect+for+Real+Estate+in+Summer+2020_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Things are heating up, and I just mean the weather...</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Things are heating up, and I just mean the weather...</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Lower Your Monthly Mortgage Payment</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-lower-your-monthly-mortgage-payment.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2020-05-05 09:15:43 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/How+to+Lower+Your+Monthly+Mortgage+Payment.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you want to lower your monthly mortgage payment, you must eliminate your private mortgage insurance.

If you’re looking to lower your monthly mortgage payment, you can do so by eliminating your primary mortgage insurance (PMI).

If you bought your home with a down payment of less than 20%, odds are you’re still paying PMI as part of your monthly mortgage payment. The only way to get rid of this is if you’ve built up at least 20% equity in your home. You can also decrease the PMI you’re paying if you’ve built up anything close to 20%.

“The more you pay down your principal balance and the higher the value of your property increases, the more your equity builds.”

Most homeowners don’t realize that they’ve already probably built up 20% equity. The more you pay down your principal balance and the higher the value of your property increases, the more your equity builds. However, this rule doesn’t apply to FHA loans. With FHA loans, your PMI is there for the entirety of the loan. 

So to determine your equity, find your home’s current market value, figure out what you owe for your principal balance, and calculate the difference. If your equity is close to or over 20%, contact your lender and tell them you want to get rid of your PMI.

As always, if you have questions about this or any real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/How+to+Lower+Your+Monthly+Mortgage+Payment.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/How+to+Lower+Your+Monthly+Mortgage+Payment.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you want to lower your monthly mortgage payment, you must eliminate your private mortgage insurance.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you want to lower your monthly mortgage payment, you must eliminate your private mortgage insurance.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Mortgage Forbearance May Not Be Wise</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-mortgage-forbearance-may-not-be-wise.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-17 14:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Why+Mortgage+Forbearance+May+Not+Be+Wise.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m discussing mortgage forbearance and why it may not be the best option. The relief opportunity of a mortgage forbearance allows you to delay payments for three months to a year. In fact, most major banks are automatically deferring payments for up to three months right now. However, you need to speak to your mortgage lender to find out when exactly those deferred payments will be due. Many lenders are expecting the deferred payments right at the end of the deferment period. To learn more about mortgage forbearance, watch the short video above.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Why+Mortgage+Forbearance+May+Not+Be+Wise.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Why+Mortgage+Forbearance+May+Not+Be+Wise.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Mortgage forbearance allows you to defer your payments, but it may cause you more problems later.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Mortgage forbearance allows you to defer your payments, but it may cause you more problems later.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Your Latest Houston Market Update</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/your-latest-houston-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-09 14:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Your+Latest+Houston+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’m sharing a current Houston real estate market update and an essential document if you’re going to be conducting real estate in the next few months.

Today I’m sharing a quick update about what’s happening in the Houston real estate market. Overall, activity has slowed down, for justifiable reasons. However, dozens of homes continue to be listed daily. I encourage you to use this essential document called the “COVID-19 Addendum” if you’re going to be involved in a real estate transaction within the next few months. You can download it here.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Your+Latest+Houston+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Your+Latest+Houston+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’m sharing a current Houston real estate market update and an essential document if you’re going to be conducting real estate in the next few months.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’m sharing a current Houston real estate market update and an essential document if you’re going to be conducting real estate in the next few months.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Happy Holidays from RE/MAX Signature</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/happy-holidays-from-remax-signature.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2019-12-18 14:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/2019/December/What+Is+Selling+Your+Home+in+the+Winter+Really+Like_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Wishing you and your family a happy holiday season.

On behalf of my team here at RE/MAX Signature, I want to wish you and your family a happy holiday season. I’d also like to acknowledge each and every one of you for trusting us with your real estate dreams, for doing business with us, and most importantly, for sending us a record-shattering number of referrals this year. We are so grateful for the opportunities you’ve given us in 2019. 

This may be a busy time of the year for us all, but feel free to reach out to me if you have any questions or need any assistance with your real estate plans. I’m always available to help! In the meantime, have a wonderful holiday season and a happy New Year!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/2019/December/What+Is+Selling+Your+Home+in+the+Winter+Really+Like_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/2019/December/What+Is+Selling+Your+Home+in+the+Winter+Really+Like_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Wishing you and your family a happy holiday season.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Wishing you and your family a happy holiday season.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Is Selling Your Home in the  Winter Really Like?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-selling-your-home-in-the-winter-really-like.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2019-12-13 14:34:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/2019/December/What+Is+Selling+Your+Home+in+the+Winter+Really+Like_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Why should you sell your home this winter? Let’s discuss.

Conventional wisdom tells us that winter is the slowest time of year for real estate and there is some truth to this. However, just because there are fewer buyers and sellers active on the market during this season, that doesn’t mean activity comes to a halt. In fact, homes tend to sell faster during the winter than any other time of year. There are two main reasons this is the case: 

1. There’s less competition among sellers. Many sellers falsely assume that this is a bad time of year to list, so they steer clear of the market until spring rolls around. This allows sellers who do make a move during the winter to stand out and command a higher level of interest thanks to the lack of options available to buyers.

2. Buyers are more serious in the winter. Because so few listings are available through these later months of the year, the buyers who do choose to start their home search in the winter are generally quite eager to strike a deal. There are also tax benefits to closing before the end of the year—namely, the Homestead Exemption. For this, and many other reasons (such as job transfers or end-of-year bonuses), winter buyers are bound to put forward some of the best buyers sellers will see all year.

“Homes tend to sell faster during the winter than any other time of year.”

If you have any other questions, would like more information, or are curious how my team and I can help you sell your home this winter, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/2019/December/What+Is+Selling+Your+Home+in+the+Winter+Really+Like_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/2019/December/What+Is+Selling+Your+Home+in+the+Winter+Really+Like_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Why should you sell your home this winter? Let’s discuss.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Why should you sell your home this winter? Let’s discuss.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Investors & Homebuyers Need to Know About Opportunity Zones</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/investors-homebuyers-need-to-know-about-opportunity-zones.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-12 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Many don’t know this, but opportunity zones were created as part of the 2017 tax reform to shore up economic activity and long-term investments within certain communities.

Opportunity zones are census tracts that are recommended by the governor and designated by the U.S. Treasury. In Houston, there are around 99 opportunity zones.

For investors, the tax advantages associated with opportunity zones are massive. One of the reasons why opportunity zones were created was to attract investors to these areas. For example, if you wanted to sell a property but you want to defer capital gains taxes, you could invest in an opportunity zone. Depending on how long you hold those properties, there are some very generous tax implications.

“For investors, the tax advantages associated with opportunity zones are massive.”

You don’t have to be an investor to take advantage of these opportunity zones. If you’re just thinking of buying a home, there are several census tracts to choose from. If you purchase a home within one of these areas, you can expect to be able to purchase a home with zero dollars out of pocket.

However, be sure to do your research. There are certain incentives that you as a homebuyer could qualify for, and make sure that you’re applying for the right programs when you buy property in these opportunity zones.

If you have any further questions about opportunity zones in the Houston area, including how to find them and what benefits they could present to your future prospects, don’t hesitate to reach out. I’d love to speak to you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What are opportunity zones, and why should investors and homebuyers know about them? Find out today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What are opportunity zones, and why should investors and homebuyers know about them? Find out today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Can Sellers Expect from an iBuyer?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-can-sellers-expect-from-an-ibuyer.html</link>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2019-10-26 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking of selling your home to an iBuyer, there are several pros and cons to consider before you move forward. 

The pros:

1. Convenience. By selling to an iBuyer, you won’t have to fix up, repair, stage, or show your home. You also won’t have to deal with deal with waiting for your home to sell as it sits on the market, which leads me to my next point…2. They’re a guaranteed buyer. You’ll face no uncertainty about closing on time or whether you’ll close at all. Also, you won’t have to deal with any contingencies—financing or otherwise. iBuyers have their own money that they use to buy from you directly. 3. It will be a quick transaction. Because it’s an all-cash purchase, you can expect the closing to take place in two or three weeks, tops.

“Remember to weigh the net proceeds you’ll receive instead of the sale price.”

The cons:

1. High fees. The tradeoff for all your convenience is high transaction fees, which range from 7% to 11.5%. In a traditional real estate transaction, your brokerage fee is between 5% and 6%. 2. Uncertainty in the offer price. When these companies make you an offer, the final price is subject to inspections and further approval. When you go under contract with them, you may have a lot of contractors show up at the home asking you to make certain repairs or adjust the sale price. With that in mind, you should expect the final sale price to be much different than the original offer price. 3. Loss of equity. Again, in exchange for all that convenience, you’ll probably sell your home for less than it’s full value. At the end of the day, whether you’re selling to an individual investor or a company like Zillow or Offerpad, the best thing you can do for yourself is shop around to find the best quote. Also, remember to weigh the net proceeds you’ll receive instead of the sale price. Even if you’re offered a high sale price, there may be transaction costs you’ll have to pay that could eat up your equity. As always, if you’d like to talk more about this topic or you have any other real estate questions I can answer, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you better off selling to an iBuyer? Here are the pros and cons to consider that will help answer that question.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you better off selling to an iBuyer? Here are the pros and cons to consider that will help answer that question.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Things to Check on a Buyer’s Walk-Through</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-things-to-check-on-a-buyers-walk-through.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2019-10-06 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
Doing a buyer’s walk-through is extremely important. A buyer’s walk-through (or a final walk-through) is a crucial step before the closing where the buyer and the real estate agent go to reexamine the property and make sure that the property is in the same condition in which they originally found it. It is not a reinspection of the property, so it shouldn’t take you multiple hours.

“A buyer’s walk-through is a crucial step before the closing.”

There are three things you need to pay attention to when conducting a final walk-through:

1. Make sure that all repairs are done. You may want to go item by item, walk through the house and confirm all the promised repairs have been addressed.

2. Determine that everything is working. For example, check that the garage opener works, the remotes are functioning, the water heater is still creating hot water, the A/C is cooling down or warming up the home, and so on. Also, verify that no moisture has gotten into the home from recent storms or floods. If any damage has been caused, it’s still the seller’s property, so those need to be addressed before it becomes yours. 

3. Establish that all negotiated items are still present. Any items that were supposed to be left for you should still be there. For example, the refrigerator, the washer and dryer, the speaker system, the alarm system, and so on. 

Do not sign on the dotted line to purchase the home until you have done all three of these things! 

If there are any questions or a topic you wish me to cover, feel free to reach out to me by phone or email, I would love to do a video on that topic for you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Find out what you need to pay attention to on a buyer’s walk-through.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Find out what you need to pay attention to on a buyer’s walk-through.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Attract Multiple Offers to Your Listing</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-attract-multiple-offers-to-your-listing.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-15 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/How+to+Attract+Multiple+Offers+to+Your+Listing+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Do you want to get more offers on your home when it hits the market? The more buyers you have looking at your property, the better your chances are of securing top dollar. 

So if attracting more traffic to your listing is something you’d like to do, then try these three tips:

“When buyers see all the other people who are interested in your home, you can be sure they’ll put their best foot forward when writing you an offer.”

1. Use professional photography. First impressions are key, and the majority of today’s buyers begin their home search online. Therefore, the photos you use to represent your property on online listings could make or break your success. These photos should not only convey the look and feel of your home, but the atmosphere of the neighborhood, as well. Thanks to drone technology, achieving this is much easier than it was in the past. 

2. Price your home strategically. It’s always better to list slightly below market value and drive demand up than to overprice your home and hope for the best. Modern buyers savvy— they know a good deal when they see one. Likewise, they know when a home is overpriced. If you want to sell above market value, the key is to price your home low. This can generate a bidding war and help you walk away with top dollar at the end of the deal. 

3. Hold a “mega open house.” By listing your property in the middle of the week but turn away showings until the weekend, at which point you’ll host an open house, the number of buyers who show up to see your home is sure to be higher than it would typically be. And when buyers see all the other people who are interested in your home, you can be sure they’ll put their best foot forward when writing you an offer. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/How+to+Attract+Multiple+Offers+to+Your+Listing+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/How+to+Attract+Multiple+Offers+to+Your+Listing+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you want to get more offers on your home, use these three tips.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you want to get more offers on your home, use these three tips.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips for Dealing With Multiple-Offer Situations as a Buyer</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-tips-for-dealing-with-multiple-offer-situations-as-a-buyer.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-07 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/3+Tips+for+Dealing+With+Multiple+Offer+Situations+as+a+Buyer+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Multiple-offer situations occur when a seller receives more than one offer for their property. They usually happen when there is a high demand but a limited supply of homes in that area’s market. In these situations, the seller’s listing agent will notify all of the homebuyers who placed an offer on the property that they have two to three days to submit their highest and best offers.

As a homebuyer, there are three things you can do that will improve your offer and increase your chances of getting the seller to accept it despite the competition:

“If you can do these three things, you will have a competitive edge over the competition in a multiple-offer situation.”

1. Accommodate the seller. Find out what the seller’s needs are so that your offer can accommodate them. Most of the time, the seller’s needs go beyond price—for example, does the seller need time to move out after closing? If you know that, you can write your offer to suit their needs, making yours more attractive in their eyes. 

2. Simplify your offer. Going in, a lot of buyers try to negotiate repairs, closing costs, and other parts of the deal with the seller. In a multiple-offer situation, never do that—keep your offer simple. Focus on the price, down payment, and closing date of your offer. The reason to keep it simple is that your objective isn’t to get a good deal, but rather to secure the contract. Once you’ve done that, you’ll have up to 10 days to negotiate all those items anyway. 

3. Have a true pre-approval. Most buyers going into a transaction will ask for up to 21 days to complete the third-party financing contingency. Essentially, buyers are asking the seller for up to three weeks of time so they can speak with their banks or mortgage lenders about getting a loan for the home. If you could ask for a smaller period of time to complete this contingency, that will help you to stand out from the crowd of other buyers. If you get a pre-approval from a lender before you make an offer, you’ll already have submitted all the necessary documents and information to them, meaning that you’ll be able to shorten your timeframe. Sellers will appreciate a reduced contingency period.

If you can do these three things, you will have a competitive edge over the competition in a multiple-offer situation.

For any questions you have about this topic or anything else to do with real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/3+Tips+for+Dealing+With+Multiple+Offer+Situations+as+a+Buyer+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/3+Tips+for+Dealing+With+Multiple+Offer+Situations+as+a+Buyer+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What can homebuyers do to come out on top in a multiple-offer situation? Stay tuned.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What can homebuyers do to come out on top in a multiple-offer situation? Stay tuned.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Houston Market Like Right Now?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-the-houston-market-like-right-now.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-20 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mustafa+Faiz/5+30+MU+Edit.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A lot of people have been asking me to explain what’s happening in our Houston market. Actually, the conditions you’ll face today will largely depend on your goals.

If you’re a buyer looking to purchase a property in the $200,000 to $400,000 price range, for example, you’ll find yourself up against a lot of competition. There’s far more demand than there is supply in that price bracket right now, so you’ll need a strong agent by your side in order to get your offer accepted. 

If you’re a seller in this price range, this high demand will definitely work in your favor. You’ll be able to sell quickly and for top dollar, thanks to the high number of interested buyers. 

In higher price ranges, though, buyers have the upper hand. The $400,000-and-up price range has a lot of inventory, which means listings will take a little longer than normal to move off the market. Sellers will need to be patient (and flexible) when looking for buyers in this price range.

If you have any other questions or would like to know more about what’s happening now in our market, feel free to give my team or me a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mustafa+Faiz/5+30+MU+Edit.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mustafa+Faiz/5+30+MU+Edit.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What’s happening now in our Houston real estate market? Find out with this quick message.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What’s happening now in our Houston real estate market? Find out with this quick message.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Let My New YouTube Channel Be a Resource for Your Real Estate Needs</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/let-my-new-youtube-channel-be-a-resource-for-your-real-estate-needs.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mustafa Faiz</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-20 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Let+My+New+YouTube+Channel+Be+a+Resource+for+Your+Real+Estate+Needs.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I’d like to take a moment to welcome you to my new YouTube channel. Here, you will find key buyer tips, seller tips, and local market updates. I truly want this page to be a resource for all of your real estate needs, so if there is a specific topic you’d like more information about, let me know. I would love to cover some of your questions in a future video.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Let+My+New+YouTube+Channel+Be+a+Resource+for+Your+Real+Estate+Needs.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mustafa+Faiz/Let+My+New+YouTube+Channel+Be+a+Resource+for+Your+Real+Estate+Needs.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Welcome to my new YouTube channel!</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mustafa Faiz</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Welcome to my new YouTube channel!</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Mustafa Faiz</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Mustafa Faiz</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from RE/MAX Signature - your professional Houston Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
